(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-10T01:25:23.261081",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
遠い。
Far.
わたしが目指す場所は、
The place I'm aiming for...
あまりにも遠い。
is far too distant.
歩いて、歩いて、歩いて、
Walking, walking, walking...
バカけた夢だろうか。
could this be a ridiculous dream?
諦める理由なら
If there was a reason to give up,
過去に捨ててきた
I left it in the past.
僕だけの栄光路を
I want to prove
証明したいんだ。
my own glorious path.
教えて 教えてよ その仕組みを
Tell me, tell me, how it works...
僕の中に 誰がいるの?
Who is inside of me?
壊れた 壊れたよ
I'm broken, I'm broken down
この世界で
in this world,
君が笑う 何も見えずに
you're laughing, seeing nothing at all.
壊れた僕なんてさ
A broken me like this,
息を止めて
holding my breath...
ほどけない もう
Can't untie it, no,
ほどけないよ 真実さえ freeze
can't untie it anymore, even the truth—freeze.
壊れる 壊せない
Can break it, can't break it,
狂える 狂えない
going mad, not going mad.
あなたを見つけて 揺れた
Finding you, I swayed.
歪んだ世界に
In this twisted world,
だんだん僕は透き通って
bit by bit, I became transparent
見えなくなって 見つめないで
and disappeared—don't look at me!
僕のことを 見つめないで
Don't stare at me...
誰かが描いた世界の中で
In a world someone else has drawn,
あなたを傷つけたくはないよ
I don't want to hurt you.
覚えていて 僕のことを
Remember me,
鮮やかなまま
staying vibrant as I am.
無限に広がる
Endless
孤独が絡む
loneliness entwines,
無邪気に笑った記憶が刺さった
innocent, smiling memories pierce through.
動けない
Can't move,
can't move,
動けない
動けないよ
can't move anymore.
変わってしまった
Things have changed,
変えられなかった
and couldn't be changed back.
unravel
壊れてしまった
It broke down,
変えられなかった
couldn't be changed back.
ふたつの絡む ふたりが滅びる
Two things intertwine, two souls perish.
壊れる 壊せない
Can break it, can't break it,
狂える 狂えない
going mad, not going mad.
あなたを汚さないよ 揺れた
I won't taint you—I swayed.
歪んだ世界にだんだん僕は
In this twisted world, bit by bit,
透き通って 見えなくなって
I became transparent and disappeared.
見つけないで 僕のことを
Don't find me, don't look at me...
見つめないで
Don't stare at me.
誰かが仕組んだ孤独な罠に
In a lonely trap someone engineered,
未来がほぐれてしまう前に
before the future comes undone,
思い出して 僕のことを
remember me vividly,
鮮やかなまま
staying just as I was.
忘れないで
Don't forget,
don't forget,
忘れないで
don't forget.
変わってしまったことに paralyze
Paralyzed by the change,
変えられないことだらけの paradise
in a paradise full of things that can't be changed.
覚えていて 僕のことを
Remember me,
見つめないで
don't look at me.
教えて 教えて
Tell me, tell me,
僕の中に誰がいるの?
who is inside of me?
誰かいるの?
Who is there?
鉄の弾が 正義の証明
An iron bullet is the proof of justice.
貫けば 英雄に近づいた
If you pierce through, you approach being a hero.
その目を閉じて 触れてみれば
Close your eyes and try to touch it—
同じ形 同じ体温の悪魔
a demon with the exact same shape and warmth.
僕はダメで あいつはいいの?
Why am I bad, while he is fine?
そこに壁があっただけなのに
Even though there was just a wall there,
生まれてしまった 運命嘆くな
don't lament the fate of being born.
僕らはみんな 自由なんだから
Because we are all free.
鳥のように 羽根があれば
If we had wings like birds,
どこへだって行けるけれど
we could go anywhere at all,
帰る場所が なければきっと
but if we have nowhere to return to,
どこへも行けない
surely we can go nowhere.
鉄の弾が 正義の証明
An iron bullet is the proof of justice,
世界は 残酷だ
The world is cruel,
それでも 君を愛するよ
Yet I still love you.
なにを 犠牲にしても
No matter what I sacrifice,
それでも 君を守るよ
I will still protect you.
間違いだとしても 疑ったりしない
Even if I'm wrong, I won't doubt you.
正しさとは 自分のこと 強く信じることだ
Righteousness is strongly believing in yourself.
鉄の雨が 降り注ぐ情景
The scene of rain falling like steel
テレビの中 映画に見えたんだ
Looked like a movie on TV.
戦争なんて 愚かな凶暴
War is a foolish, brutal thing,
関係ない 知らない国の話
A story from a country I don't know.
この言葉も 訳されれば
Even these words, if translated,
本当の意味は 伝わらない
Won't convey their true meaning.
信じるのは その目を開いて
Believing is opening your eyes
触れた世界だけ
And touching only that world.
ただただ 生きるのは嫌だ
I don't just want to live.
世界は 残酷だ
The world is cruel,
それでも 君を愛するよ
Yet I still love you.
なにを 犠牲にしても
No matter what I sacrifice,
それでも 君を守るよ
I will still protect you.
選んだ人の影 捨てたもののかばね
The shadow of the chosen, the corpses discarded,
気づいたんだ 自分の中 育つのは悪魔の子
I realized a child of the devil grows inside me.
正義の裏 犠牲の中心には 悪魔の子
Behind justice, at the heart of sacrifice, is a child of the devil.
聞いてくれて ありがとうございます！
Thank you for listening!
そして、角巻わため 生誕祭2024 リバイバルを見に来てくれて ありがとうございます！
And thank you for coming to see Tsunomaki Watame's 2024 Birthday Live Revival!
今日でなんと、わためは8歳になりました！いぇーい！
Today, believe it or not, Watame turned 8 years old! Yay!
みんなの応援があってこそ 迎えられた8歳だと思います。
I feel like I could only reach 8 years old thanks to everyone's support.
あー、おめでとうも、ありがとう！いっぱいいっぱいありがとうございます。
Ah, congratulations and thank you! Thank you so, so much.
もう本当に、わためをいつも支えてくれて感謝してもしきれないぐらいです。本当にありがとう！
I truly can't thank you enough for always supporting Watame. Thank you so much!
今日はね、ちょっと暗めの、闇深い曲から始まりましたが、見てくれているみんなと、そしてゲストのみんなと一緒に、さらにいろんな音楽を巡って、そしてリバイバルしていきたいと思いますので、今日は素敵なライブにしましょう！
Today, we started with a somewhat dark, deeply profound song, but I want to journey through even more kinds of music together with everyone watching and our guests, and do a revival, so let's make this a wonderful live!
あ、そういえば、このモニター！すごかったでしょ？今まっくろだけどね。
Oh, come to think of it, this monitor! Wasn't it amazing? It's pitch black right now, though.
これ、途中で変身したんだけどさ、あと2回？いや、3回？いや、4回、何回だったかな？このモニターが変形するので、ぜひびしバシ！スクショ撮ってほしいなと思います。
I transformed midway through, but... 2 more times? No, 3? No, 4 times, how many was it? This monitor transforms, so I'd love for you to take lots of crisp screenshots!
そして、シャープ、角巻わため 生誕祭2024で、たくさんポストもしていただけると嬉しいです！
And I'd be happy if you posted a lot with the hashtag #TsunomakiWatameBirthdayLive2024!
ラストには、告知！
And lastly, announcements!
そして、そのあとは面会ライブもありますので、最後までぜひ楽しんでいってください！いぇい！
And after that, there's also a meet-and-greet live, so please enjoy it all the way to the end! Yay!
次の曲にいっちゃいまーす、いいかな？
Shall we go on to the next song?
いいかな？
Is that alright?
いいよー！
Yeah!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
では、次はロリな、あの曲いきます！
Now, for the next one, we're doing that loli song!
ロンリーロリロリ神降臨
Lonely loli-goli goddess, descend!
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
Ring the bell and follow the way,
これは救済のレクイエム
This is the requiem of salvation.
せーのっ
Ready, set!
触ったら逮捕!(Ah!)
Touch me and you're arrested! (Ah!)
極chu♡de点呼!(Uh!)
Extreme census with a kiss! (Uh!)
いちにーさんしー? でゅおれ?
One, two, three? (De solé?)
ごめんなさいが聞こえなーい
Sorry, I can't hear your excuse!
粛聖!! ロリ神レクイエム☆
Holy!! Loli-gami Requiem☆
将来は お前なんかに出逢いたくない
In the future, I don't want to meet anyone like you.
泥水で口を洗え
Wash your mouth in the mud.
法廷で会おう?
See you in court? ♡
さあ おまわりさん 連れて行って
Come on, officer, take him away!
妄想しか取り柄のない かわいそうな人
You pitiful person with nothing but delusions!
(ういちゃん！ういちゃん！待ってよ ういちゃん！)
(Ui-chan! Ui-chan! Wait, Ui-chan!)
その姿親に見せられますか？
Can you show that appearance to your parents?
(ういちゃん！ういちゃん！かわいい ういちゃん！)
(Ui-chan! Ui-chan! Cute Ui-chan!)
わぁ、ありがとうございます！
Oh, thank you very much!
お疲れ様です～
Well done~
ロンリーロリロリ神降臨(ずっきゅーん!)
Lonely loli-goli goddess, descend! (Zuk kyun!)
マジヤバ奴等に用心(ばっきゅーん)
Watch out for those dangerous freaks (Bak kyun!)
まともじゃないなら 早く消えてください
If you're not normal, disappear quickly!
lonely ロリロリ神降臨(ずっきゅーん!)
Lonely loli-goli goddess, descend! (Zuk kyun!)
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り(yes!)
Ring the bell and follow the way (yes!)
とても優しくて 素敵なお兄ちゃん
Such a kind and wonderful big brother,
楽園でホラ ねんねしな (ういちゃん…)
Don't sleep in paradise... (Ui-chan...)
ほら。世の中には、こんなに気持ち悪い人たちが蔓延してるんですっ！
Look. In this world, such disgusting people are running rampant!
みーんな、晒し age しますよ。
Everyone, let's expose and shame them!
(ういちゃん…うい、こっち向いてぇ~~~)
(Ui-chan... Ui, look over here~~~!)
触ったら逮捕!(Ah!)
Touch me and you're arrested! (Ah!)
極chu♡de点呼!(Uh!)
Extreme census with a kiss! (Uh!)
いちにーさんしー? でゅおれ?
One, two, three? (De solé?)
ごめんなさいが聞こえなーい
Sorry, I can't hear your excuse!
粛聖!! ロリ神レクイエム☆
Holy!! Loli-gami Requiem☆
はぁーい、獄中にいるみなしゃーぁん
Hiii, everyone in prison!
刑務所ファミリーミーティングのお時間でぇーす
It's prison family meeting time!
その、腐りきった耳をゴリゴリかっぽじって
So, clean out those rotten ears
よおーく聞いてくださいね
and listen carefully!
ざぁーこ (助かる〜っ)
Trash! (That helps~)
きもきも (助かる〜っ)
Repulsive! (That helps~)
うるさい (助かる〜っ)
Noisy! (That helps~)
黙ってもらっていいですか？
Can you stay quiet?
嫌いです (助かる〜っ)
I hate you! (That helps~)
かわいいそう (助かる〜っ)
Too bad! (That helps~)
だーきっ よーうっ みっともな〜w
Love ya! Hey-yo! Pathetic, haha!
どうしようもない お兄ちゃんお姉ちゃん
You big brothers and sisters who are totally hopeless,
もう希望もない ゴミだなめら
You are already trash, garbage disposal!
おばけしょうらく 100とうばん
Ghost elimination, 110 emergency call,
こうゆうきょうこ こっそりと
Exclusive barrier, opening and closing secretly ♡
刑務所ファミリーミーティングのお時間でぇーす
It's prison family meeting time!
その鎖切った耳を ゴリゴリかっぽじって
So, clean out those ears with the broken chains,
よおーく聞いてくださいね
and listen carefully!
ざぁーこ (助かる〜っ)
Trash! (That helps~)
きもきも (助かる〜っ)
Repulsive! (That helps~)
うるさい (助かる〜っ)
Noisy! (That helps~)
おまえたち (助かる〜っ)
You guys! (That helps~)
きらいです (助かる〜っ)
I hate you! (That helps~)
かわいいそう (助かる〜っ)
Too bad! (That helps~)
ざぁさ よわ みっともな
Well, weak, and pathetic!
どうしようもない お兄ちゃんお姉ちゃん
You big brothers and sisters who are totally hopeless,
もう希望もない ゴミだなめら
You are already trash, garbage disposal!
おばけしょうらく 100とうばん
Ghost elimination, 110 emergency call,
こうゆうきょうこ こっそりと
Exclusive barrier, opening and closing secretly ♡
礼拝堂でほら 年々死な
In the chapel, look, dying year after year.
世の中にはこんな気持ち悪い人たちがはびこっているんです
In this world, such disgusting people are running rampant!
みんな、さらさら晒しあげちゃいますよ！
Everyone, let's expose and shame them!
さわったら逮捕！極chu♡de点呼！
Touch me and you're arrested! Extreme census with a kiss!
いち・に・さん・し？
One, two, three, four?
でゅおれ？
(De solé?)
ごめんなさいが聞こえない！
Sorry, I can't hear your excuse!
粛聖!! ロリ神レクイエム☆
Holy!! Loli-gami Requiem☆
なにかの勘違いじゃない、もっと近くに来なさい
It's no misunderstanding, come closer!
刑務所湾ミーティングのお時間です
It's prison bay meeting time!
その鎖切った耳を ゴリゴリかっぽじって
Clean out those ears with the broken chains,
よおーく聞いてくださいね
and listen carefully!
ざーこ、きもきも
Trash, repulsive!
うるさい、黙ってもらっていいですか？
Noisy, can you stay quiet?
嫌いです、かわいそう
I hate you, too bad!
ざーさよわは みっともない！
Weak, and pathetic!
おしまいのお兄ちゃんお姉ちゃん
Big brothers and sisters whose time is up,
もう希望もない ゴミだなめら
You are already trash, garbage disposal!
おばけしょうらく 100とうばん
Ghost elimination, 110 emergency call,
こうゆうきょうこ こっそりと
Exclusive barrier, opening and closing secretly ♡
礼拝堂などないから
Because there is no chapel,
大きな友達のみんなへ
To all my big friends out there,
おまえらが打ち込んでいる日々には
What is the meaning of the days you pour your efforts into?
何の意味があるの？ねえ教えてよ
Hey, tell me!
私って全然わかんないんだ！
I don't get it at all!
ロンリーロリロリ神降臨(ずっきゅーん!)
Lonely loli-goli goddess, descend! (Zuk kyun!)
さようなら笑顔でバイバイ(ばっきゅーん)
Farewell with a smile, bye-bye! (Bak kyun!)
ピリオドをどうぞこの手で押してあげゆ
Let me press the period with this hand!
lonely ロリロリ神降臨(ずっきゅーん!)
Lonely loli-goli goddess, descend! (Zuk kyun!)
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り(yes!)
Ring the bell and follow the way! (yes!)
とても優しくて 素敵なお兄ちゃん
Such a kind and wonderful big brother,
楽園などないから
Because there is no paradise...
触ったら逮捕!(Ah!)
Touch me and you're arrested! (Ah!)
極chu♡de点呼!(Uh!)
Extreme census with a kiss! (Uh!)
いちにーさんしー? でゅおれ?
One, two, three? (De solé?)
ごめんなさいが
Sorry,
聞こえなーい
I can't hear your excuse!
粛聖!! ロリ神レクイエム☆
Holy!! Loli-gami Requiem☆
本当に気持ち悪っ
Seriously, totally gross.
どうして みんなが 幸せなの?
Why is everyone so happy?
この世界のこと 聞きたいって 知りたいって
Wanting to know about this world, wanting to learn about it,
水辺の公園で みんなが耳を澄ませて
At the waterside park, everyone strains their ears,
わくわくするね ねえ、オンディーヌ?
How exciting, right, Undine?
はい はーい!
Yes, yes!
さあさあ、みなさん 教えてあげまーす!
Now, everyone, let me tell you!
みんなが気になってること 疑問に思ってること 全部 教えてあげまーす!
Everything you're curious about, everything you're wondering—I'll tell you all of it!
えー、みなさんが 幸福なのは… 義務なんです。
Um, everyone being happy... is an obligation.
幸せですか? 義務ですよ? 果たしていますか?
Are you happy? It's an obligation, you know? Are you fulfilling it?
我々、幸福安心委員会は みなさまの幸せを願い そして、支えまーす。
We, the Happiness Security Committee, wish for your happiness and support you.
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is an obligation.
幸せですか? 義務ですよ?
Are you happy? It's an obligation, you know?
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is an obligation.
幸せですか? 義務ですよ?
Are you happy? It's an obligation, you know?
ですから、安心して義務を果たすように!
Therefore, rest assured and fulfill your obligation!
みなさまの幸せが 我々の幸せ。
Your happiness is our happiness.
幸せですか? 義務ですよ? 果たしてますか?
Are you happy? It's an obligation! Are you fulfilling it?
幸せじゃないなら…
If you aren't happy...
絞首 斬首 銃殺 釜茹で 溺死 電気 火あぶり 生き埋め 薬殺 石打ち 磔
Hanging, decapitation, firing squad, boiling, drowning, electrocution,
burning, burying alive, lethal injection, stoning, crucifixion...
好きなのを 選んでね♪
Choose your favorite♪
はい はーい!
Yes, yes!
さあさあ、みなさん 幸せだけが満ちてまーす!
Now, everyone, only happiness fills the room!
不安とか 不満、なにし一つないでしょ?
No anxiety or dissatisfaction whatsoever, right?
こわーく、恐いわ 幸せすぎて、恐いわ。
It's so terrifying—being too happy is terrifying.
ホントに みんなが 幸せなの?
Is everyone really happy?
この世界の外 行きたいって、逃げたいって
Wanting to go outside this world, wanting to escape,
水辺の公園で みんなが耳を塞いで
At the waterside park, everyone covers their ears,
びくびくしてた ねえ、アンディーヌ?
Trembling in fear, right, Undine?
はい はーい!
Yes, yes!
さあさあ、みなさん 死にましたー!
Now, everyone, you've died!
オンディーヌをふった騎士は 死にましたー!
The knight who rejected Undine has died!
葬儀に出るなら、向こうに並べ!
If you're attending the funeral, line up over there!
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is an obligation.
幸せですか? 義務ですよ?
Are you happy? It's an obligation, you know?
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is an obligation.
幸せですか? 義務ですよ?
Are you happy? It's an obligation, you know?
義務なんです 義務ですよ?
It's an obligation, an obligation, you know?
義務なんです 幸福なのは義務なんです
It's an obligation, being happy is an obligation.
義務なんです 義務ですよ?
It's an obligation, an obligation, you know?
義務なんです 幸せじゃないなら 死ね
It's an obligation—if you aren't happy, die.
忘れてしまったこと
I've forgotten so much already,
ことだけを覚えている
just remembering that much.
ぽかりと空いたあんなの先の端で君と出会った
It's as if Tokyo Tower, reflecting in the window, has gotten a little closer.
名前も顔も分からない君なんだか
Since I can listen to anyone's worries,
懐かしいような気がした
I've even learned how to give plausible answers.
互いにあんな待ってゆくように
Memories overflow from what I threw away,
ふざけ合って 笑い合って
and mistaking a shrunken heart for being an adult has become so easy.
どこかにいる君のため
Only the way to say goodbye passes right through me,
今愛して生きているよ 僕ら
and yet only a lonely smile is something I can't quite erase.
mumeいのまま
I hope we can meet somewhere again.
たとえばこれが写し出された幻でも
Even if this were all a projected illusion,
確かに感じる今君がそこにいること
I can definitely feel right now that you are here.
名前も顔も分からない君さようならしてしまえば終わりだ
If I just said goodbye to you, whose name and face I don't even know,
would it all be over?
君がいなきゃ穴は大きくなる構わないさ すぐ見つかる
If you're not here, the hole will just get bigger, but I don't care, it'll choke me soon.
どこにいるの 今ここにいるよ
Where are you now, you who are somewhere out of reach?
あたし
I'm right here.
mumei
ふたりは一面真っ暗な世界 真っ逆様に落ちていく
The two of us are in a pitch-black world, falling upside down.
mumeiだからこの世界には忘れられ球場の
Mumei, so in this world, there is a forgotten playground.
それでも君が求めるのなら この胸に開いた穴には
Even so, if you seek it, open the hole in this chest.
ここから新しい世界へと扉の景色を今君の中で描く
From here on, I'll tear through reality and recreate that universe right here inside you.
どこかにいる君のため
Where are you now, you who are somewhere out of reach?
今愛して生きているよ 私mumeいのまま
I am living right now, just as I am, with you.
名前のない怪物
[Title: Namae no Nai Kaibutsu]
作詞・作曲: ryo(supercell)
[Music: ryo (supercell)]
御伽話は さっき死んだみたい
The fairy tale died just a moment ago,
煉瓦の病室でうまく歌えなくて
unable to sing well in this brick hospital.
霧に煙る夜浮かべ赤い月
A red moon floats in the foggy night.
ほらみて 私を
Look, see me,
目を逸らさないで
don't look away.
黒い鉄格子の中で
Inside the black iron bars,
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born.
悪意の代償を願え
Pray for the retribution of malice,
望むがままにお前に
and as you wish, to you...
さあ与えよう正義を
Here, I give you justice!
壊して 壊される前に
Destroy them before you are destroyed,
因果の代償を払い
pay the price for karma,
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
and let's go together, nameless monster.
耳鳴りがしている
My ears are ringing,
鉄条網うるさくて
the barbed wire is noisy.
思い出せないの あの日の旋律
I can't remember that day's melody.
雨はまだやまない
The rain still hasn't stopped,
何にも見えないの
and I can't see a thing.
ほらみて こんなに大きくなったの
Look, see how big it's grown.
黒い雨降らせこの空
Let black rain fall from this sky,
私は望まれないもの
I am an unwanted existence.
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis...
愛する同罪の傍観者達に
to beloved bystanders sharing the same guilt.
さあ今振るえ正義を
Now, show me your justice,
消せない傷を抱きしめて
embracing unerasable scars,
この身体を受け入れ
accepting this body,
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
let's go together, nameless monster.
神ハ告ゲル 真ノ世界ヲ
God proclaims the true world.
黒い鉄格子の中で
Inside the black iron bars,
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born.
悪意の代償を願え
Pray for the retribution of malice,
望むがままにお前に
and as you wish, to you...
さあ与えよう正義を
Here, I give you justice!
壊して 壊される前に
Destroy them before you are destroyed,
因果の代償を払い
pay the price for karma,
報いよ 名もなき怪物
repay them, nameless monster.
黒い雨降らせこの空
Let black rain fall from this sky,
私は望まれないもの
I am an unwanted existence.
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis...
愛する同罪の傍観者達に
to beloved bystanders sharing the same guilt.
さあ今振るえ正義を
Now, show me your justice,
消せない傷を抱きしめて
embracing unerasable scars,
この身体を受け入れ
accepting this body,
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
let's go together, nameless monster.
神ハ告ゲル...
God proclaims...
真ノ世界ヲ
the true world.
黒い鉄格子の中で
Inside the black iron bars,
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born.
悪意の代償を願え
Pray for the retribution of malice,
望むがままにお前に
and as you wish, to you...
さあ与えよう正義を
Here, I give you justice!
壊して 壊される前に
Destroy them before you are destroyed,
因果の代償を払い
pay the price for karma,
報いようなき怪物
without even a reward, you monster.
黒い雨降らせこの空
Let black rain fall from this sky,
私は望まれないもの
I am an unwanted existence.
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis...
愛する同罪の傍観者達に
to beloved bystanders sharing the same guilt.
さあ今振るえ正義を
Now, show me your justice,
消せない傷を抱きしめて
embracing unerasable scars,
この身体を受け入れ
accepting this body,
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
let's go together, nameless monster.
いつだってそう「僕なんて」さって
Always wishing, "If only I were..."
俯いてばっかりのMayday
Huddled away in a Mayday of hesitation.
つまづいて泣いて 「どうせ」って口癖が染みついてさ
Whining and crying, "Whatever," became a habit.
いつからかまた積もる焦り
Before I knew it, impatience was piling up again.
でも胸の奥にある光
Yet, the light deep within my chest
繋ぐ点と線の上
Connecting the dots and lines,
踏み出すイメージの先へ
Stepping forth toward the edge of my imagination.
遠くたっていい ほら 虹をまたいで
Far away is fine, look, transcending the rainbow,
さあ 心のままに音を奏でる
Now, let your heart play the music freely.
逸る鼓動は今を刻む証だ
This racing heartbeat is the proof of marking the present.
響け 僕らの想いを乗せて
Resound, carrying our feelings,
高く遠く 歌を紡いで
Spinning a song high and far,
Lalala
季節巡って 駆け抜けて
Seasons revolving, running through,
気づけば大人になって
Before I knew it, I had grown up.
幼い日の心は胸の奥潜んでた
The feelings of my early days were hiding deep in my heart.
怖いことも増えたけれど
Things to fear had also increased, but...
でも今だから見える世界
Even so, the world visible only now,
僅かの中に確かり灯る光
A light gleaming steadily within the smallness.
繋いでいこう
Let's keep connecting them.
さあ 新しいステージへ
Now, onto a new stage,
心の中の音を聴かせて
Let the music inside your heart be heard.
大袈裟でいい
It's okay to be grand,
ありのままの自分で
Being your true self,
咲き誇れもっと
Blooming proudly even more.
歌いながら日々を紡いで
Spinning the days while singing.
俯いて泣いた日もあった
There were days when I huddled and cried,
だけど涙も力になる
Even tears can become strength.
刻れ HEART 鳴らせ BEAT
Carve the HEART, sound the BEAT.
響け僕らのメロディ
Resound, our melody!
ねえ あの日の夢も 今の自分も
Hey, the dreams of that day and the self of today,
描く未来も 全て抱きしめるよ
The future we draw, we embrace it all.
さあ 旅を続けよう
Now, let's continue our journey,
どこまでもしずずっと 手を繋いで
Holding hands forever and ever wherever we go,
ほら 僕らの一歩だ
Look, it's our first step.
心のままに音を奏でる
Now, let your heart play the music freely.
逸る鼓動は今を刻む証だ
This racing heartbeat is the proof of marking the present.
響け 僕らの想いを乗せて
Resound, carrying our feelings,
高く遠く 歌を紡いで
Spinning a song high and far,
Lalala
季節巡って 駆け抜けて
Seasons revolving, running through,
気づけば大人になって
Before I knew it, I had grown up.
幼い日の心は胸の奥潜んでた
The feelings of my early days were hiding deep in my heart.
怖いことも増えたけれど
Things to fear had also increased, but...
でも今だから見える世界
Even so, the world visible only now,
僅かの中に確かり灯る光
A light gleaming steadily within the smallness.
繋いでいこう
Let's keep connecting them.
さあ 新しいステージへ
Now, onto a new stage,
心の中の音を聴かせて
Let the music inside your heart be heard.
大袈裟でいい
It's okay to be grand,
ありのままの自分で
Being your true self,
咲き誇れもっと
Blooming proudly even more.
Hey, unhappy wild ようこそ楽園へ
Hey, unhappy wild, welcome to the madness,
Into this order 吸い込まれていく
Into this order, we are swallowed up.
地球もそろそろ周り疲れて
The earth is also beginning to be exhausted all around.
Awe, JABBERWOCKY いつまで転がる？
Awake, JABBERWOCKY, until when will we keep rolling?
人間臭く繰り返される営み
The repeating everyday life of human karma,
退屈せずStep to the scene
Boring sin, step to the scene.
世界をごちゃ混ぜにして呑み込め！
Mix up the world and swallow it down!
悪意が僕を寂してやまない
Evil is holding me tight, I can't stop!
hey unhappy world
ようこそ 楽園へ
Welcome to paradise.
into disorder
吸い込まれていく
being sucked in.
地球もそろそろ回り疲れて飽きちゃう
The earth is getting tired of spinning and bored.
ねぇ いつまで転がる？
Hey, how long will it keep rolling?
輪廻転生 繰り返される 営み
The cycle of rebirth, repeated actions.
つまんない整数と統制
Boring integers and control.
奇と正をごちゃまぜ 混ぜ盛りあがれ
Mixing odd and even, get excited in chaos.
悪意が僕を
Malice
魅了してやまない
captivates me.
ガラスの靴だわ
Glass slippers,
履いたなら綺麗ね
so beautiful when worn.
罪の重さで木端微塵
Shattered to pieces by the weight of sin.
愛したいな 生かしたいな
I want to love, I want to live,
壊したいな 殺したいな
I want to destroy, I want to kill.
世界が僕らを嫌うなら
If the world hates us,
左胸で踊り狂う臓器
organs dancing wildly in the left chest,
今際にしがみついて閊る
clinging on the brink, throbbing.
赤い目して踊り騒ぐ wake me up
With red eyes, dancing and making a fuss.
残酷は天使のツラして 憂いながら弄んだ
Cruelty disguised as an angel, toying with sorrow.
弱者敗者 ふみつけて
Trampling on the weak and losers,
psycho さぁ行こう
PSYCHO, now let's go.
治療してよ
Treat me,
カルテはめちゃくちゃ
my medical records are a mess.
刺してほら
Stab me, look,
その細かい針
with that thin needle.
「不可解」つたえない落書きでも
\"Incomprehensible,\" even with clumsy scribbles,
純真無垢でしょ？
isn't it pure innocence?
これがお好きでしょ？
You like this, right?
毒に染まる愛
Love tainted with poison,
直情的な恋
impulsive romance.
僕はどこまでいけるのか
How far can I go?
醜いな 汚いな
Ugly, dirty,
美しいな 素晴らしいな
beautiful, wonderful,
時代よ僕を受け入れな
Oh era, accept me.
うるさいさっきも聞いたよ愚者
Noisy, heard it just now, fools.
ストレス社会あっそほんかで？
Stressful society, really?
僕はひたすらこの楽園を生き抜いてやろう
I will simply survive in this paradise.
左胸で踊り狂う臓器
Organs dancing wildly in the left chest,
うるさいさっきも聞いたよ
Noisy, heard it just now,
わがままんな
so selfish.
ストレス社会遊んで
Stressful society, having fun,
僕はひたすらこの楽園を
I will simply survive in this paradise.
生き抜いてやろう
...
左胸で踊り狂う臓器
Organs dancing wildly in the left chest,
今際にしがみついて閊る
clinging on the brink, throbbing.
赤い目して踊り騒ぐ wake me up
With red eyes, dancing and making a fuss.
残酷は天使のツラして 憂いながら弄んだ
Cruelty disguised as an angel, toying with sorrow.
治療してよ カルテはめちゃくちゃ
Treat me, my medical records are a mess.
刺してほら その細かい針
Stab me, look, with that thin needle.
残酷は天使のツラして 憂いながら弄んだ
Cruelty disguised as an angel, toying with sorrow.
僕がいつか切れるまで ただ遊べ
Until I get bored someday, just play.
hey losers, this is my paradise
弱者敗者 ふみつけて
Trampling on the weak and losers,
psycho 最高
PSYCHO at its best.
When you look up at the night sky what do you see?
The glowing beauty in the twilight its no mystery
Now watch me set the scene I'll light it all up when the time has come I'll be rising high
Longing for me like a lifeline whenever you see my shine I'll catch your eye
It's pulling you in like gravity
You will be bowing on your knees, yeah
Watch my glory and might following me like a high tide
My reign will never stop the tide begins to rise up to the top
Let my power ignite following me like a high tide
I can be a bright enigma it's no surprise
But you'll give in to the brilliance like a moth to a light
Playing hard to get but I ain't patient you'll succumb to my blinding radiance, yeah
When you look up at the night sky what do you see?
My shine! An effulgent sight
Watch my glory and might following me like a high tide
My reign will never stop the tide begins to rise up to the top
Let my power ignite following me like a high tide
Following me like a high tide...
The way the waves come down
I catch your eye
It's pulling you in like gravity
You will be bowing on your knees, yeah
Pulling you in, close to me
Watch my glory and might, following me like a high tide
My reign will never stop, the tide begins to rise up to the top
Let my power ignite, following me like a high tide
Following me like a high tide
mayday 声は届いてる？
Mayday, is my voice reaching you?
心がざきっと痛いみたい
It feels like my heart is painfully aching
babyなんて魅力的 魅せるテクニックはすぐにクラクラ
Baby, how charming. The mesmerizing technique makes my head spin
mayday それじゃ物足りない すぐにもっともっと欲張るスタイル
Mayday, that's not enough. A style that instantly wants more and more
ah 見え隠れした甘い罠
Ah, sweet traps hidden from view
ah ハマってあげようか
Ah, shall I fall for them?
ah 自在にコントロールしていたはずなのに
Ah, even though I should've been controlling it freely
クラクラって酔い出しそうな甘い匂い誘われ
Lured by the sweet scent that makes my head spin,
フラフラって寄ってきちゃうわ ああもう help me
I stagger right over, ah, help me already.
逃れたいわけじゃなくて
It's not that I want to escape,
これくらいがちょうどいいわ なんて
thinking 'this much is just right,' but...
もうキミの前じゃ絶対 help meして
Right in front of you, absolutely, help me.
蘇えらせるのさ
Bring it back to life,
愛するキミの心
your beloved heart.
体を脱ぎ捨てて 今輪廻に帰る時
Shedding this body, now is the time to return to the cycle of reincarnation.
回りゅーれ ガラエ サダナレ アマレ
Swirling, breaking away, calming down, overflowing,
ディレヒ ジュマギ ガナショラ
letting go, spinning around, dancing away.
回りゅーれ ガラエ サダナレ アマレ
Swirling, breaking away, calming down, overflowing,
手に触れて 覚醒
touching it, awakening.
目を潰って 風を救って
Closing my eyes, catching the wind,
身を溶かして 金を鳴らして
melting my body, ringing the bell,
回りゅーれ ガラエ サダナレ アマレ
Swirling, breaking away, calming down, overflowing,
ディレヒ ジュマギ ガナショラ
letting go, spinning around, dancing away.
十字架がしゃらまはり
Crosses clatter and spin around,
いわれがやへ さばかれ あまれ どらひ
heading to where reasons lie, judged and rained down,
十字架がしゃらまはり
crosses clatter and spin around,
いわれがやへ さばかれ あまれ どらひ 天に吠えて
heading to where reasons lie, judged, howling to the heavens—
覚醒 レイメイは
Awakening, the dawn is...
何度も 埋もれどへを 駆ける 歌のソウル
Running again and again toward a place to live, the soul of song—
闇を越えて 飛び出せ
jump across the darkness and leap out!
十字架がしゃらまはり
Crosses clatter and spin around,
いわれがやへ さばかれ あまれ どらひ
heading to where reasons lie, judged and rained down,
十字架がしゃらまはり
crosses clatter and spin around,
いわれがやへ
heading to where reasons lie—
いついつまでも 照らすはこの地で 歌おうわ
No matter when, let's sing in this illuminated land,
胸を打ち震わせる 感動を
to make the emotion that shakes our chests echo,
鳴らすように
ringing out,
いつの日か もしも灯火が消え去ったって
so that even if someday the lamp's light goes out,
人が生きていくなら 歌おうわ
if people are to keep living, let's sing—
心は 死なない すべてが壊れても
our hearts will never die, even if everything breaks!
行き止まった 牢獄から
From a dead-end prison,
香り出すのは 火薬と死の匂いさ
what exudes is the scent of gunpowder and death.
じゃあ 進め
Well then, move forward!
朽ち果てた 荒野なりに 吹きすさぶ風
In the ruined wasteland, the raging wind
哀しみ責めるなら 叫べ
if sorrow torments you, scream out!
ぜんぶ
Everything—
朝が来たって 振り続く 雨だとざす
Even if morning comes, the rain keeps falling and locking in—
おもかげ 狭い あの歌を 今あと片も無き
memories... that narrow song, now leaving not a trace,
この地で
in this land.
歌おうわ わずかでも かすかでも
Let's sing, even if just a little, even if faintly,
また希望を 信じたいから
because I still want to believe in hope.
奏でだし 溢れ出す あの笑顔を取り戻せるなら
If I can bring back that smiling face that overflows with melody,
私の歌は やまない
my song will never stop.
この声枯らすまで
Until this voice grows hoarse—
変わり果てても 変わらないものがあると
Even if it transforms completely, believing there is something that never changes,
目を閉じ 浮かべて あなは 叫べ
close your eyes, picture it, and scream out—
まだ共に鳴らせる 心があるなら
if there is still a heart that can echo together,
何ひとつ 無駄じゃない
not a single thing is in vain.
この歌も この愛も 耳色のがらんどをも
This song too, this love too, and the echoing emptiness of my ears—
どこまでも 響いてたとしても 今はただ空しいだけ
even if they resonate to the ends of the earth, right now they feel so empty,
でも願いを込めて
but putting a wish into it—
人の歌を 絶やしたものが 人の主役
The one who extinguished human song, the protagonist of humanity—
私 知っても 歌おうわ
even knowing that, let's sing!
さあ 後ろ盾も無くこの地で
Come on, without any backing in this land,
歌おうわ ただ強く なお強く まだ希望を
let's sing, just stronger, still stronger, still holding onto hope,
信じたいから 奏でだし 溢れ出す
because I want to believe in it, melody starts overflowing,
あの笑顔を取り戻せるなら
if I can bring back that smile,
私の歌は やまない この声枯らすまで
my song will never stop, until this voice grows hoarse.
滅びたこの街で
In this ruined city—
叫べよ 叫べ
scream out, scream!
はあ、ありがとう！
Phew, thank you!
いや、ここまで駆け足でたくさんの歌を聞いていただきましたが、みんな楽しんでますか？
We rushed through and listened to so many songs so far, but are you all having fun?
わためはめちゃくちゃ楽しいです！
Watame is having an absolute blast!
いや、本当に歌を歌わせてくれてありがとうございます。
Yeah, thank you so much for letting me sing.
そしてなんと、次の曲でラストになります。
And amazingly, the next song will be our last.
寂しい！寂しい！寂しい！
I'm lonely! So lonely! So lonely!
本当に寂しいんかってね。
Are you really that lonely, huh?
寂しい、けど！ここで嬉しいお知らせがあります。
I am, but! I have some happy news to share.
今から歌わさせていただく曲は、わためが作詞をした新曲『Revival』という曲です。
The song I'm about to sing is my new self-written track, "Revival".
そして、わためセカンドライブでお披露目をした『メーデーメーデー』『フィーチャリング 森カリオペ』が音源になりまして、『リバイバル』と一緒にこのあと24時、24時から楽曲配信されます！
And what's more, "Mayday Mayday" featuring Mori Calliope, premiered at my 2nd live, is now available as a single! It'll be released digitally right at midnight alongside "Revival"!
『リバイバル』と『メーデーメーデー』『フィーチャリング 森カリオペ』是非買ってください、よろしくお願いします！
Please make sure to buy "Revival" and "Mayday Mayday" featuring Mori Calliope. Thank you so much!
では、歌うか。寂しいけど、みんなに聴いてもらいたい新曲、魂を込めて歌いたいと思います。それでは聴いてください。新曲『リバイバル』。
Well then, time to sing. Even though I'm sad, I want to put my soul into this new song I want you all to hear. Please listen to my new song, "Revival".
壊したい衝動
An urge to destroy,
崩れていく感情
emotions falling apart,
彩、失った眼光
gaze stripped of all color,
突きつける銃口
muzzle pointed straight at me.
マジメな者が馬鹿を見る世界
A world where the earnest play the fool,
全てを僕から奪ってよ
take everything away from me.
どうしてアイツは見下し笑うの？
Why do they look down and laugh at me?
叫んだ怒号も届かない
My shouted roars don't even reach them.
泣き叫んで泣き喚いて
Crying, screaming, howling,
救いを求めて
begging for salvation,
切り裂いて振り払って絡まる糸を解いて
slashing and shaking off, untangling the threads,
囚われて縛られて消えない痛みに
trapped and bound by unending pain,
その手で抱きしめて生きる意味を教えて
hold me tight and teach me life's meaning!
本当は愛したいな
The truth is, I want to love,
この胸を焦がすほど 夢を笑われても
burning this chest, even if my dreams are mocked,
努力否定されても 踏みつけられてでも
even if my efforts are denied, even if I'm trampled down,
(笑って 笑って)
(Laugh, just laugh)
何が正解なの？僕にはわからないよ
What is the right answer? I have no idea.
感情なんてもういらないよ
I don't need emotions anymore.
涙など枯れ果てて この世を憎んで
Tears run dry, cursing this world,
噛みついて傷つけて
biting and hurting,
赤い眼に映して
reflecting in crimson eyes,
記憶して刻み込んで消えない痛みを
memorizing and carving in the pain that won't fade,
ねえもう誰でもいい 生きる意味を教えて
Hey, anyone is fine, teach me the meaning of life!
今
Now!
微かに聞こえる声 闇夜を切り裂く声
A faint voice is heard, a voice tearing through the dark night,
さあ今一歩を踏み出せ
Now, take that step forward!
切り裂く声
A voice that tears through...
さあ 今 一歩を踏み出せ
Now, take that first step forward!
重くても 辛くても
No matter how heavy or painful it is,
もう一度 立ち上がれ！
stand up once again!
駆け抜けて 手を伸ばして 光を求めて
Run through, reach out your hands, seeking the light.
大丈夫、少しずつ ありのままで
It's alright, little by little, just as you are.
転んでも這い上がって 夜に呑まれても
Even if you fall and crawl back up, swallowed by the night,
流した涙さえ 力に変えていく
turn even the tears you shed into strength.
この命 燃え上がれ
Blaze up, this life of mine!
僕はまだ 終わりじゃない
I'm still not finished yet.
何度でも 何度でも
No matter how many times, no matter how many times,
僕だけの 人生を 始めよう
let's begin the life that is uniquely mine.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
生誕祭ライブ、いかがだったでしょうか？
How did you like the birthday live?
楽しんでもらえていたら嬉しいです。
I hope you enjoyed it.
ここでいくつか告知をさせてください。
Now, please allow me a few announcements.
角巻わための新曲「Revival」が
Tsunomaki Watame's new single "Revival"
このあとすぐホロライブチャンネルにてMV投稿されます
will have its MV posted on the Hololive channel shortly,
そして、なんとこの後24時から
And what's more, starting at 24:00 tonight,
楽曲配信もあります！
there will also be a song release!
新曲「Revival」と「mayday, mayday」の2曲！
The two tracks: "Revival" and "mayday, mayday"!
たくさん買って聴いてください。よろしくお願いします！
Please buy and listen to them a lot. Thank you!
そして、お誕生日といえば！誕生日記念グッズが今年も出ます！
And speaking of birthdays! Birthday merch is out this year too!
詳細はこらら！まずは「2層アクリルパネル」！
Details are here! First is the 2-Layer Acrylic Panel!
今年もふみママに描き下ろししていただきました！
Drawn by Fumi-mama again this year!
君と色違いのリュックを背負って海べデートがテーマです！
Theme is a beach date with matching backpacks!
そして、わためと色違いの「わためとリュック」！
Next, the "Watame & Backpack" in matching colors!
色は黒で大きめサイズ。だけど軽くて使いやすいです！
Black and fairly large, but light and easy to use!
リュックにつけたりできる「缶バッジ」4種類1セット！
"Can Badges" for your backpack in a set of 4!
どれも可愛いので、ぜひ身の回りのものにつけてください！
They're all cute, so please attach them to your things!
さらに、「わためほっぺむにむにキーホルダー」！
Plus, the "Watame Squishy Cheek Keychain"!
ほっぺをつかまれているわためがキーホルダーになりました！
Watame with her pinched cheeks became a keychain!
フルセット購入特典は直筆サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカード！
Full set bonus: signed postcard with a message!
数量制限なしで書かせていただきますので、ぜひ買ってね！
Written with no quantity limits, so please buy it!
このあとすぐメンゲンライブもやりますのでぜひ見にきてね！
We'll also have a member-only live right after this!
みんなが支えてくれるおかげで今年も色々なことに挑戦できています。
Thanks to your support, I can take on new challenges.
いつも応援してくれるわためいとも、今日初めて知った方も、
To loyal Watamates and those who just discovered me today,
8歳になったわためをこれからもよろしくお願いします！
please keep supporting 8-year-old Watame!
ではメンゲンライブの準備をしてくるのでみんな待っててね！
I'll go prep for the live, so everyone wait for me!
またあとでね！
See you later!